

Sominath Wagh

Software Developer and Data Analyst

Analytical and solution-oriented post-graduate with 3+ years of experience in translating business requirements and functional specifications into code modules and software solutions. Seeking a position to proactively contribute to the development and maintenance of software applications in a fast-paced work environment.

xominathwagh456@gmail.com

Ujjain, MP, India

github.com/sominathwagh456

9960414424

20 December, 1994

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Avantika University (MIT Group), Ujjain 🗹

10/2021 - Present

- Analyzing data and preparing reports for the institutional audit and accreditation.
- Developed purchase requisition module (using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap for frontend; PHP for backend; and MySQL as the database)
- Provided application (Superset, a SAAS platform) support to the Career Services team and maintained the database.

Associate Ops - Mortgage

WNS Global Services, Pune 🗷

10/2020 - 06/2021

- Handled and streamlined back-office processes in the Mortgage Loan Processing.
- Provided timely resolutions to the customer queries as per the process guidelines.

C# Developer Intern

Zibew, Hyderabad 🗷

10/2019 - 01/2020

- Developed a web application on the .NET framework for an NGO to manage and track their contacts, donors, projects, and campaigns.
- Created web-pages (using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS), developed mechanism for daily data recovery, and maintained their databases.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. (Computer Science)

ASM College of Commerce, Science & Information Technology, Pune

05/2016 - 04/2019 Aggregate: 61.59%

B.Sc. (Computer Science)

Late T.D. Pathare College, Pune 🗷

05/2012 - 10/2015 Aggregate: 57%

HANDS-ON WITH

Programming Languages: C, C++, PHP, C#

Database: SQL Server

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript

Operating System: Window 7, 10

ENTREPRENEURIAL PURSUITS

Sai Tour & Travel Services, Pune (07/2015 - 09/2017)

- Built a web application to handle the booking transactions, customer loyalty, export excel reports, and dashboard for metrics.
- Designed and implemented strategies to expand the customer base, which resulted in a 50% increase in monthly sales.

Yuwa Sangharsh

 Co-founded a social work group in Pune for brainstorming over the problems that plague our nation, designing solutions that address those problems, and implementing them.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Library Management System

Developed a web application (using Java) to handle various library functions such as registrations, stocking, maintaining records of returned books.

Car Dealership Management System

Developed an e-commerce web application on the .NET framework (using c#, SQL, HTML, and CSS) that shows available cars with their specifications to reduce walk-ins at the car dealer centers.

LANGUAGES

English • • • • •